A Guide to the Allen L. Louderback papers, 1992-2005 (bulk 2000-2005)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Allen L. Louderback papers, 1992-2005 (bulk 2000-2005)
The Library of Virginia
42536
2.1 cu. ft. (6 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Allen L. Louderback, February 2006.
Biographical Information
Allen L. Louderback was born 12 March 1948 in Luray, Virginia and attended Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University (Virginia Tech). He served as an investigator and manager at the Government Accounting Office (GAO). In 2000 he was elected to the Virginia House of Delegates as a Republican for the 15th District, which includes the Counties of Page, Rappahannock, Rockingham (part) and Shenandoah, serving until he retired in 2005. He served on the Agriculture Chesapeake and Natural Resources, Finance, and Military Police and Public Safety Committees. After leaving the House Louderback serves as a management consultant.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1992-2005 (bulk 2000-2005), of Allen L. Louderback, member of the Virginia House of Delegates representing the 15th District. Includes copies of amendments and bills, correspondence, newspaper clippings, notes, reports, resolutions, and studies. Topics include ABC stores, education, electricity deregulation, environment, taxation, and transportation. Of note are the House Bills and House Joint Resolutions for which Louderback was chief patron, including HB 280 [Vehicle License plates], HB 281 [Special License plates], HB 282 [Library boards in Shenandoah County], HB 283 [Failure to comply with court ordered visitation], HB 1167 [Sales and use tax exemption, Woodstock Museum of Shenandoah County], HB 1169 [Sales and use tax exemption, Deer Rapids Road Fund Trustees], HB 1214 [State Employee Suggestion Award Program], HB 1267 [Privatization of ABC Stores], HJ 195 [Commending Rappahannock County for its outstanding volunteer efforts], HJ 237 [Commending Town of Woodstock for 250th Anniversary], HB 238 [Commending Page County High School boys' cross-country team], and HB 239 [Commending Rappahannock County High School softball team].
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Legislative bills, 2001-2005
Series II: Subject files, 1992-2005
Contents List
- Series I: Legislative bills, 2001-2005., Extent: .70 cu. ft. (2 boxes). (Box 1-2)
  This series includes copies of amendments and bills, correspondence, newspaper clippings, notes, reports, and resolutions relating to specific House Bills, House Joint Resolutions, and Senate Bills. Of note are bills to revise the state tax code, franchising of ABC stores, and bills affecting the 15th District.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 2001, HJR 685/SJR 387, Joint Subcommittee to Study and Revise the State Tax Code. (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - 2002, HJR 161, Karst Groundwater Monitoring Shenandoah Valley. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2003, HB 1592, Virginia Distribution Center Department of General Services. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 2003, HB 1985, ABC Board to Study and Implement Retail Franchising. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2004, HB 30, Budget Appropriations, Amendments. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 2004, HB 58, Luray-Page County Airport. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 2004, HB 108, Tax reform (TRIM). (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 2004, HB 141, Election of Page County at Large. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 2004, HB 142, ABC Retail Franchising. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 2004, HB 2175, Regulation of Mopeds. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 2004, HB 2178, Shenandoah National Park License Plate. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 2004, HB 2179, Combat Infantry Badge. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 2004, HB 2493, Local Reimbursement for Sludge Monitoring. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 2004, HB 2492, Tax reform. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 2004, HJ 247, State Waste Empowerment and Enforcement Provision Act,. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 2004, HJ 659, Exclude Privately Owned Motor Vehicles from Property Taxation. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 2004, HJR 336-337, Page County High School Cheerleaders Commendation and Page County High School Cross Country Team Commendation. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 2004, HR 5004, Income and Sales Tax Preferences. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 2005, HB 1498, ABC Stores, Retail Franchising. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 2005, HB 1500, Budget Appropriations, Amendments. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 2005, HB 2176, Town of Stanley Charter. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 2005, HB 2777, Retail Sales and Use Tax; increased, creates Water Quality Improvement Restricted Use Fund. (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
  - 2005, HB 2809, Menhaden Management Measures. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 2005, HB 2882, Agency Savings. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 2005, SB 750, Rail Transportation Development Authority; created. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series II: Subject files, 1992-2005., Extent: 1.4 cu. ft. (4 boxes). (Box 2-6)
  This series includes correspondence, minutes, newspaper clippings, proposals, and reports relating to the various bills and resolutions found in Series I. Topics include ABC stores, education, electricity deregulation, environment, taxation, and transportation.
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - ABC Stores, 2000-2002. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - AOSE (Authorized Online Soil Evaluator), 1992-2002. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts, 2004. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth Competition Council, 2003. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Commonwealth Competition Council, 2004. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Commission of Efficiency Effectiveness, 2002. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cost Cutting Issues, 2001-2005. (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - DMV, 2002-2003. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Education, 2003. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Education and School Construction Concepts, 2001-2002. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Electricity Deregulation, 2001-2003. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Parks, 2003. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - State Tax Code Study, 2002. (Box 4, Folder 2-7)
  - Tax issues, 1999-2005. (Box 5, Folder 1-7)
  - Tax issues, Report on the Commission on Virginia's State and Local Tax Structure for the 21st Century, House Document No. 22, 2001. (Box 6, Volume 1)
  - Tax issues, Report of the Joint Subcommittee To Study and Revise Virginia's State Tax Code, House Document 26, 2003. (Box 6, Volume 2-3)
  - Tax issues, Who Pays? A Distributional Analysis of the Tax Systems in All 50 States, 2003. (Box 6, Volume 4)
  - Transportation, 2002-2003. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Department of Transportation [VDOT], 2000. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Virginia State Water Commission, 2003-2004. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 2001 Proposed Legislation. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 2002 Proposed Legislation. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 2003 Proposed Legislation. (Box 6, Folder 6)